Christian Larwood

chrislarwood@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/chrislarwood

github.com/christianlarwood

PROFILE

I am a Software Engineer based in Boston, MA, and the co-creator of Jolt (<u>iolt-framework.github.io/</u>), an open-source framework that easily deploys JAMstack applications with serverless functions. I have multiple years of experience in both JavaScript and Ruby and am comfortable working with PostgreSQL, Node, and AWS cloud infrastructure.

EXPERIENCE

Jolt, Co-Creator & Software Engineer

2021-Present

Jolt is a lightweight, open-source framework for deploying and managing JAMstack applications with serverless functions.

- Designed the AWS microservices architecture, prototyped, and built Jolt with Node.js using the AWS Node SDK to deploy AWS cloud infrastructure (S3, Lambda, CloudFront, DynamoDB, IAM, API Gateway).
- Co-designed and developed a proxy using Lambda@Edge for routing relative path requests from CloudFront to AWS API Gateway; enabling predictable and consistent API endpoints for users.
- Implemented versioning of static assets and APIs to allow users to update and rollback applications; resulting in a simplified user experience and reuse of existing infrastructure to prevent unnecessary billing charges.
- Contributed to an atomic deployments feature that utilizes a runtime object to track all provisioned AWS resources in order to handle deployment failures.
- Created the CLI tool (commander, JavaScript) for developing, deploying, and maintaining Jolt applications to improve the developer experience of our users.
- Led the creation of and presented a technical demo of Jolt to an audience of 50+.
- Produced the front-end assets (100+) for the Jolt whitepaper, website, and presentation using Sketch.
- Collaborated with a remote team of 3 other engineers across 3 time zones to build Jolt.
- Co-authored Jolt's comprehensive technical case study.

Self-Employed, Software Engineer

2020 - 2021

- JAMnotes a CRUD notes app built using the JAMstack architecture (AWS, faunaDB, HTML & CSS)
- COREbin a real-time RequestBin clone for debugging webhooks (Node.js/Express, Redis, HTML & CSS)
- Trollo a Trello-like collaboration app (React/Redux, Node.js/Express, MongoDB)
- Todos a todo tracker (Node.is/Express, JavaScript, ¡Query, Handlebars, HTML & CSS)

Intuit, Business Operations - Business Performance, Strategy, & Growth Analyst

2017 - 2019

 Partnered cross-functionally within the Small Business & Self-Employed Group to help identify numerous problems and opportunities and executed 7 high-priority projects including sizing & analyzing growth opportunities (international markets, customer segments, and strategic initiatives).

Square Inc., Caviar Fastbite Operations Manager

2015 - 2016

 Managed a fleet of 100+ couriers including all aspects of recruiting & hiring, training, scheduling, pay, equipment & inventory, support, and off-boarding. Executed major operational improvements such as reduced operating losses (73% in 4 mo.) and order growth (3x in 6 mo.) in the San Francisco market.

Lyft Inc., Market Launcher & Operations

2013 - 2015

Launched operations in 11 markets improving time to launch by 60% (2mo to 3wks with 7x the results). Conducted in-depth market research to build a go-to-market strategy for each market including marketing & comms, pricing, growth strategies (driver and passenger), and operations (demand/supply management).

SKILLS

Languages

Technologies

JavaScript, Ruby, SQL, HTML, CSS

 $HTTP, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, faunaDB, REST\ APIs,$

Webhooks

Frameworks

Cloud

Express.js, Handlebars, React/Redux, jQuery, Sinatra

AWS (Lambda, DynamoDB, S3, CloudFront, IAM), Heroku

EDUCATION

Launch School (launchschool.com/employers)

2020 - 2021

A multi-year full-stack mastery-based Software Engineering curriculum. Learned Ruby, JavaScript, SQL, HTTP, HTML, and CSS

San Diego State University

2006 - 2009

B.S. in Business Administration - Finance